raytheon.com 2019-11-11

# Privacy | Raytheon

### EFFECTIVE DATE: March 20, 2019.

This Privacy Notice applies to any visitor of our websites (hereinafter referred to as "Visitors"), as well as to Raytheon customers and business partners (collectively referred to as "You") as specified below. Our websites include, in particular, [www.raytheon.com](http://www.raytheon.com/), [www.raytheon.com/au/](http://www.raytheon.com/au/), [www.raytheon.com/uk/](http://www.raytheon.com/uk/), [www.raytheon.com/cyber](http://www.raytheon.com/cyber), [http://investor.raytheon.com](http://investor.raytheon.com/), [raytheon.mediaroom.com](http://raytheon.mediaroom.com/), [jobs.raytheon.com](https://jobs.raytheon.com/), [www.mathalive.com](http://www.mathalive.com/), [www.mathalive-me.com](http://www.mathalive-me.com/), and any other websites (singularly and collectively, "the Site") that Raytheon owns and controls, except those websites or applications that maintain a separate privacy statement (such as the [Rcareers privacy policy](https://tbcdn.talentbrew.com/company/4679/v1_0/img/Raytheon_Careers_Privacy_Policy.pdf) at www.[jobs.raytheon.com](https://jobs.raytheon.com/), the privacy policy for [Rstars](ttps://raytheon.rstars.com/Home/Index), and the [privacy policy](https://www.raytheon.com/sites/default/files/2019-03/NexGenTrac%20App%20Privacy%20Policy%2003062019.pdf) for the NextGenTrac Mobile Application). 

Raytheon Company and its subsidiaries and affiliates (singularly and collectively, "Raytheon", "we", "us" and/or "our") are sensitive to the issue of confidentiality in online and offline dealings and are committed to transparency regarding its protection of individual privacy. This Privacy Notice is intended to inform You about the general approach Raytheon uses in collecting, using and disseminating personal information via the Site and offline through our interactions with You via business dealings, and other activities.

Additionally, as the Site includes [www.mathalive.com](http://www.mathalive.com/) and [www.mathalive-me.com](http://www.mathalive-me.com/), which may be of interest to children under the age of 13 years old (the "Children's Sites"), we are committed to complying fully with the U.S. Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"). Parents of children who are under the age of 13 should ensure that they understand our approach to personal information, as described in this Privacy Notice, before entering any personal information on or through the Children's Sites. 

Back to Top 

**1\. What Personal Information May Be Collected via the Site and Why?**

The Sites are operated on behalf of Raytheon Company located in the USA. At Raytheon, it is our policy to create Site content that demonstrates our respect for Visitors' privacy and allows us to understand our Visitors. We may request personal information from You as a Visitor, including Your name, home address, email address or telephone number, when You interact with the Site, such as to respond to Your requests or to enable You to register to use certain features of this Site or to be provided with certain services offered via the Sites. Raytheon may process such personal information in order to provide the Site and its services (including marketing services) to You, to monitor compliance with this Privacy Notice, any other terms and conditions applicable to Your usage of the Sites and with applicable laws, for security purposes and to set up access permissions to certain other pages on the Site.

Back to Top 

**2\. Other Types of Information That May Be Collected via the Site and Why**

**2.1 IP Addresses**

An internet protocol address, or IP address, is automatically assigned to Your computer when You access the internet, and is used by web servers to identify Your computer. When You access our Site as a Visitor, we may log Your computer's IP address. We log the IP address for system administration purposes, for auditing the use of the Site, and for collecting statistical information for marketing and other purposes. Additionally, we may use Your IP address to identify a particular Visitor if we believe it is needed to enforce compliance with the terms of this Privacy Notice, any other terms and conditions applicable to Your usage of the Sites and with applicable laws or to protect our company, employees, Sites, or customers.

**2.2 Cookies or Tracers**

We may place information on Your computer to allow us to identify You. This information is known as a "cookie." We use cookies to view information about Your activities on our Sites, such as Your preferences or which pages You have visited on the Site, date and time of Your visit, Your referral page and the pages You visit after Your visit of our Sites, and Your browser settings. By understanding how and when our Visitors use the Sites, we can continually improve our Sites, as well as our products and services. Your browser may have controls that allow You to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

We use tracking scripts or "tracers" that recognize a unique identifier from a cookie placed on Your computer by another non-Raytheon website. These are used by Raytheon to gauge the success of our own advertising. For instance, we may use a tracer to determine whether You visit our recruiting pages after visiting a career site where Raytheon placed a banner advertisement. We do not use tracers to gather information on Your use of the internet unrelated to Raytheon, or to determine Your personal information.

Raytheon may use an advertising server developed by a third party to display ads on the Site. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are set by third parties (advertisers, sponsors). We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they contain. This Privacy Notice does not cover any use of information that a third-party ad server may have collected from You.

**2.3 Web Beacons**

Web beacons are small files that we may place on our Site, which count the number of unique Visitors that have visited a specific page on the Site and the number of times a given page has been displayed. This information is collected generally in the aggregate and is not linked to any personal information (except as described below).

**2.4 Pixel Tags**

We may use "pixel tags," or short pieces of code, to better measure the effectiveness of our content. These also allow social networks and other services to deliver content to You based on Your visit to our website.

**2.5 Custom URLs**

We may track Your visit by providing You with a unique universal resource locator, or URL, via an e-mail, a letter or other communication. When You use this unique URL, our website registers Your visit. We use this information to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and other content with You.

**2.6 Do-Not-Track**

Our information collection practices operate as described in this Privacy Notice independent of any "do-not-track" choice You make.

Back to Top 

**3** **.** **What Personal Information May Be Collected Offline from Customers and Business Partners and Why?**

**3.1 Personal Information about Customers**

If You are a representative or other personnel member of a Raytheon customer, or an individual customer, the Raytheon entity with whom You are interacting may collect and process as a data controller and data owner the following categories of personal information about You through our engagements with You: Your name; personal/work contact information; photograph (where permitted by applicable law); employee, contractor, or government identification; country of origin; nationality; content of communications in our exchanges regarding customer service; computer usage information related to a customer's use of its own company equipment, systems, and other resources, Internet Protocol (IP) address or other device location information of a desktop, laptop or other devices used by or on behalf of a customer to access the customer's computer or telecommunications network of Raytheon onsite or through a remote connection; and other personal information incidentally accessed on customer's equipment or systems in connection with its managed security and professional services. We process customer personal information for the following purposes: general business administration; managed security and professional services; speech recognition and call center analytics; customer support; direct marketing (e.g., email, text message, postal mail, behavioral advertising); fulfilment of requests; tracking payment of order; customer relationship management; responding to inquiries; and exercising a right or obligation imposed by law or contract (e.g., mandatory reporting obligations). Please contact Raytheon Company below in order to obtain further details on the Raytheon entity that is Your data controller / data owner in this context. 

**3.2 Personal Information about Business Partners**

If You are a representative or other personnel member of a Raytheon business partner, or individual business partner, the Raytheon entity with whom You are interacting may collect and process as a data controller and data owner the following categories of personal information about You: Your name; address; professional contacts or organizations; date of birth; photograph (where permitted by applicable law); applicable ID number (passport or national ID); qualifications; work history; job title; educational history; prohibited party or other criminal background information. We process such business partner personal information for the following purposes: general business administration; account management; IT helpdesk and support services; direct marketing (e.g., email, text message, postal mail); exercising a right or obligation imposed by law or contract (e.g., mandatory reporting obligations); and vendor management. Please contact Raytheon Company below in order to obtain further details on the Raytheon entity that is Your data controller / data owner in this context.

Back to Top 

**4\. Use of Information**

**4.1 Website-related Use of Information and Use of Information relating to Business Partners and Customers**

Raytheon may use Your personal information only as set forth herein (especially in Section 1).

Data collected via the Sites using cookies, tracers, web beacons, pixel tags and similar technologies may be analyzed in the aggregate to determine collective characteristics of Visitors, to understand traffic patterns, sales information and behavior of Visitors on the Sites. Such information also may be shared in the aggregate with third parties for advertising purposes, to enhance the Site, to enhance our products and services, and to analyze how and where best to use our resources.

**4.2 Use of Information for Monitoring and Compliance Purposes relating to the Site**

Although Raytheon is under no obligation to monitor the Site, we may monitor, store, review and share with third parties any information, including Your personal information, obtained on or through the Site, including if it is needed or requested to satisfy any applicable governmental law, regulation, investigation or proceeding. 

**4.3 Sharing of Information**

Raytheon transfers, discloses or shares Your personal information with its affiliates as necessary for the purposes stated therein. 

Generally, Your personal information will not be shared with third parties not affiliated with Raytheon. From time to time we may transfer, disclose or share Your personal information with third parties that Raytheon has engaged specifically to handle and deliver certain online activities or other support services, including, but not limited to, conducting contests and sweepstakes, hosting or marketing services. Such third parties will receive Your personal information needed to perform these functions, but we do not allow them to use it for other purposes without Your consent. When You provide Your personal information to Raytheon in response to a contest, sweepstake, or other project consistent with our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.raytheon.com/legal/), You may thereby consent that we publicly disclose and use Your personal information, as permitted by applicable law. 

Raytheon transfers business partner personal information for the purposes described in Section 1 moreover to the following types of third parties: ethics investigations providers, financial transaction messaging providers, legal advisors, document management systems providers, screening and escalation services providers, and network and IT support providers. Raytheon transfers customer personal information for the purposes described in Section 1 moreover to the following types of third parties: financial transaction messaging providers, and legal advisors.

Raytheon may also disclose Your personal information to courts, governmental and law enforcement authorities, legal counsel and similar third parties (1) where such disclosure is required or permitted by law; (2) to protect Raytheon's legal rights to the extent authorized or permitted by law; or (3) in an emergency where the health or safety of You or another individual may be endangered.

Raytheon may transfer personal information in connection with the sale or acquisition of one or more of our businesses or subsidiaries to a different company that agrees to offer equivalent safeguards for the use and disclosure of such information.

Back to Top 

**5\. Security of Personal Information Collected**

We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information You provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.  While Raytheon makes extensive effort to prevent unauthorized access to personal information, the security of information transmitted via the internet cannot be guaranteed. Any information disclosed online can potentially be collected and used by others aside from the intended recipient. Thus, Raytheon cannot warrant that Your personal information will not be disclosed to or accessed by unauthorized parties.

Back to Top 

**6\. Your Privacy Choices/Updates to Your Information**

**6.1** We offer You certain choices in connection with the personal information we collect from You. To update Your preferences, ask us to remove Your personal information from our mailing lists, exercise Your data privacy rights or submit a request, please contact us as indicated below in Section 13. 

**6.2** To the extent provided by law, You may request access to the personal information we maintain about You or request that we correct, amend, delete, restrict or block the personal information. Where provided by law, You may withdraw at any time with effect for the future any consent You previously provided to us or object at any time on legitimate grounds to the processing of Your personal information, and we will apply Your preferences going forward.

**6.3** In compliance with applicable law, we may reject Your request if we need to retain Your personal information, to enforce the terms of this Privacy Notice, resolve disputes, or provide information to satisfy applicable investigations or proceedings. Additionally, Your personal information may be retained in back-up files created by our network's back-up systems. However, we will not keep Your personal information longer than is necessary to achieve these purposes. 

**6.4** To exercise Your privacy choices for marketing emails, please click the opt-out link on the email You received or contact us via email at [PrivacyPolicy@raytheon.com](mailto:PrivacyPolicy@Raytheon.com?subject=Raytheon.com%20Opt-Out). Please indicate if You would prefer that we use a different email address or communication method. Restricting our contact methods may make it more difficult for us to keep You informed about new products, services and websites that can benefit You. These choices do not apply to transactional or relationship emails or the display of online advertising. You can revoke Your choice at any time by contacting us using one of the methods provided.

Back to Top 

**7\. External Links**

**7.1** The Site may provide links to other independently owned, controlled, and/or managed websites whose content we believe will be of possible interest and value to our Visitors. In many cases, these links represent cooperative projects or mutual links established with the organizations connected with these websites. We don't control the content of the third party websites accessed by You via these links on our Sites. These third party websites may send You their own cookies, collect data, or solicit personal information. Once You leave our Site (You can generally tell on which Site You are by checking the URL in the location bar on Your browser), the provision and use of any information You provide is governed by the privacy statement of the operator of the website You are visiting. That privacy statement may differ from ours. If You can't find the privacy statement of any of these websites via a link from that website's home page, You should contact that third party website operator directly for more information.

**7.2** To the extent that the Site includes third-party advertisements, the privacy statement of the advertiser providing the advertisement will govern the use of Your personal information collected during Your access to the advertisement. While we identify sponsor and advertiser areas of our Site, we do not control these cookies or the content of these third parties. Raytheon does not control linking practices of advertisers or sponsors and does not monitor or claim responsibility for any content or privacy practices of such websites. Once You have left our Site, You must read the privacy statement of the advertiser or sponsor to see how Your personal information will be handled.

**7.3** Raytheon may use the Site as an entry into other networked web pages and websites operated by Raytheon (together, the "Transaction Sites"). Please note that an individual Transaction Site may adopt privacy terms particular to the purpose of such Transaction Site or the transaction(s) taking place on such Transaction Site. As Transaction Sites are generally affiliated with commercial transactions that You or Your business may have with Raytheon or Raytheon affiliates, particularly those which are password-protected or subject to subscriptions, the privacy terms governing such Transaction Sites may be supplemented or superseded by specific privacy statements and/or agreements.

**7.4** We specifically recommend that children check with their parents before connecting to any new websites.

Back to Top 

**_Country, State and Regional Specific Data Privacy Information_**

**8\. Children's Privacy (COPPA) in the US**

We have implemented additional privacy safeguards when we collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. 

**8.1** Raytheon encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children. We urge parents to instruct their children not to provide their real names, email or physical addresses, or telephone numbers online without the permission of a parent or guardian. We recognize a special obligation to protect personal information obtained from children, as may be collected on the Children's Sites only. We fully comply with the U.S. Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 ("COPPA"), which requires us to take special precautions when collecting personal information from children under the age of 13.

**8.2** In compliance with COPPA, we have adopted the following policies to help keep children safe.

  * Any personal information we collect from children under the age of 13 will be used solely by Raytheon or its agents for internal purposes only and will not be sold or otherwise distributed to third parties.
  * We will not knowingly allow children under the age of 13 to access any social media site that may exist on the Site, email accounts, or other services within Raytheon that would allow them to publicly post or otherwise distribute personal information.
  * We will not knowingly ask a child under the age of 13 to divulge more information than is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service.
  * We will not knowingly keep any personal information that is inadvertently included in a child's email submission, help inquiry, or other one-time request, if we know that the child is under the age of 13. Information will be automatically purged or purged immediately after the issue has been resolved.
  * We will not knowingly post any personal information that is inadvertently included in a child's submission to a general audience contribution area if we know that the child is under the age of 13. These submissions will be deleted and handled anonymously thereafter.
  * We will not knowingly provide any direct link to websites that are unsuitable for children or teens.
  * Upon request, we will provide a parent or guardian with a description of the information that may have been provided about their child during a registration process for a program, service or contest on the Site.

**8.3** Consistent with COPPA, there are several instances in which we collect information from children, such as:

  * Requesting the contact information of a parent or guardian for the sole purpose of notifying the parent or guardian;
  * Collecting children's contact information on a one-time basis, such as when they enter a contest or ask Raytheon a question using the "contact us" link on our Sites. We will use this information on a one-time basis solely to directly respond to the child's request. We will purge the child's contact information from our systems when we have fulfilled the request, such as after we respond to the child's email or when a contest is over. We will not use children's information to re-contact them or for any other purpose other than fulfilling their requests;
  * Collecting a child's contact information and the contact information of his/her parent or guardian solely to respond directly more than once to a specific request from the child (for example, to satisfy the request for a newsletter subscription). In this instance, the parent or guardian will be notified that the child made such a request and be informed of the information provided by the child. The parent or guardian will have an opportunity at any time to revoke the child's request (i.e., unsubscribe). We will not use the child's personal information to re-contact the child for any other purpose; and
  * Using cookies to collect non-personally-identifiable information on our child-directed Sites for analytics and internal operations purposes.

Back to Top 

**9\. Your California Privacy Rights**

California's "Shine the Light" law permits California residents to annually request and obtain information free of charge about what personal information is disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. Raytheon does not distribute Your personal information to outside parties for their direct marketing, or any other purpose, except as provided for in this Privacy Notice, without Your consent. See also Section 4, Use of Information.

Back to Top 

**10\. European Union/European Economic Area and Switzerland**

If You are located in the European Union ("EU") / European Economic Area ("EEA") or otherwise protected by European data protection law, the following applies.

**10.1 EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework**

To provide an adequate level of protection for personal information received from the EU/EEA, Raytheon participates in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework ("Privacy Shield" or the "Framework").  Raytheon adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information transferred from the EU and the United Kingdom to the United States, which includes personal information about Raytheon EU employees, job applicants and individual contacts of business partners and customers. We provide notice to EU employees through separate internal company policies, and to job applicants through our recruiting and job posting websites. We are committed to subjecting such personal information to the Privacy Shield, including its Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.

We may transfer the personal information we collect to recipients in countries other than the country in which the information originally was collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which the information was initially provided. 

If there is any conflict between the terms in this Section on Privacy Shield and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern to the extent of the conflict. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/), and to located and view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

**10** **.1.1 Choices**

In addition to the rights provided under local law, You are afforded under Privacy Shield a specific right to access Your personal information. You may also have the right to exercise choices (opt-out) from our use of Your personal information for direct marketing purposes. To exercise this right, please follow the instructions in any direct marketing message You may have received. We do not otherwise use or disclose Your personal information in a manner that is subject to choice requirements under the Framework. 

**10.1.2 Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability**

Please contact us as specified below in Section 13 if You have any questions, need access to Your personal information, or otherwise need assistance. We remain responsible for our collection, use and disclosure of Your personal information in accordance with the Framework. We also are responsible for third party agents that are processing such personal information on our behalf, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose Your personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.

If You have an unresolved concern about Your personal information that we have not addressed satisfactorily, we have committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU Data Protection Authorities to serve as our independent dispute resolution body for the Framework. We are also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission with respect to the Framework. In addition, under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield [website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), individuals may invoke binding arbitration for non-monetary issues when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**10.1.3 Contact Us**

Please contact us using the contact information under in Section 13 below if You have any questions related to the Framework, wish to exercise Your rights of access, or wish to seek other assistance as described above.

**10.2 Additional Information under the EU General Data Protection Regulation**

This Section provides additional information as required by the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR").

**10.2.1 Data Controller and Legal grounds for the processing**

If You are a Visitor of the Sites, Raytheon Company as identified in Section 13 is the data controller of Your personal data. If You are a business partner or customer, the Raytheon entity with whom You interact is the data controller. Please contact Raytheon Company in order to receive the contact details of such other Raytheon entity acting as Your data controller.

Raytheon relies on the following legal grounds for the processing of Your personal information as provided under the GDPR:

  * The processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of You which require protection of personal data, in particular if You are a child; such legitimate interests are the provision of the Sites and its services as requested by You, the promotion and advertisement of our services, communicating with you, and compliance with legal obligations and internal policies and procedures (Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR)
  * Your consent to the processing of Your personal information for one or more specific purposes; 
  * the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which You are a party or to take steps at Your request prior to entering into a contract;
  * the processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject;

The provision of Your personal information is typically not required by law or contract and is therefore voluntary. However, if You do not provide Your personal information, Raytheon may not be able to make the Site and its services available to You and to response to Your request or inquiry. Similarly, if You have entered or want to enter into a contract with Raytheon, Your personal information may be necessary to pursue this purpose. 

**10.2.2 International transfers.**

Raytheon is located in the US and You therefore need to expect that Raytheon and other recipients of Your personal information are located outside the EU/EEA.

  * Raytheon and its US affiliates are certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and thereby recognized as providing an adequate level of data protection from a European data protection law perspective.
  * Other recipients located outside of the EU/EEA are also certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or are located in countries with adequacy decisions pursuant to Art. 45 GDPR (in particular, Canada (for non-public organizations subject to the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act), Switzerland, Israel), and, in each case, the transfer is thereby recognized as providing an adequate level of data protection from an European data protection law perspective. 
  * Other recipients might be located in countries which do not adduce an adequate level of protection from an European data protection law perspective (in particular, certain recipients in the USA which are not certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield). We will take all necessary measures to ensure that transfers out of the EU/EEA are adequately protected as required by applicable data protection law. 
    * With respect to transfers to countries not providing an adequate level of data protection, we will base the transfer on appropriate safeguards, such as standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission or by a supervisory authority (Art. 46(2)(c) or (d) GDPR), approved codes of conduct together with binding and enforceable commitments of the recipient (Art. 46 (2)(e) GDPR), or approved certification mechanisms together with binding and enforceable commitments of the recipient (Art. 46 (2)(f) GDPR). You can ask for a copy of such appropriate safeguards by contacting us as set out in Section 13 below.
    * The data transfers to Raytheon affiliates and other third-party service providers which are neither certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield nor in a country with other adequacy decision are typically protected by standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission (Art. 46(2)(c) or (d) GDPR).

**10.2.3 Retention Periods**

Your personal information is stored strictly to the extent necessary for the performance of our obligations and strictly for the time necessary to achieve the purposes for which the personal information is collected, in accordance with applicable data protection laws. When Raytheon no longer needs to use Your personal information, we will remove it from our systems and records and/or take steps to properly anonymize it so that You can no longer be identified from it (unless we need to keep Your personal information to comply with legal or regulatory obligations to which Raytheon is subject). 

Personal information will in principle be deleted 3 years after the last interaction and business contact between You and Raytheon, unless a longer retention is necessary to protect our interests. However, we will retain Your contact details and interests in our products or services for a longer period of time if Raytheon is allowed to continue sending You marketing materials. 

**10.2.4 Your Rights under GDPR**

In addition to or supplementing the rights set out above in Section 5 and 9, You have the following rights under GDPR: (i) request access to Your personal information; (ii) request rectification of Your personal information; (iii) request erasure of Your personal information; (iv) request restriction of processing of Your personal information; (v) request data portability; (vi) object to the processing of Your personal information (including objection to profiling), and (vi) withdrawal of Your consent at any time. Below please find further information on Your rights to the extent that the GDPR applies. Please note that these rights might be limited under the applicable local data protection law.

  * **Right to request access to Your personal information:** As provided by applicable data protection law, **** You have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not personal information concerning You is being processed, and, where that is the case, to request access to the personal information. This access information includes – inter alia – the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal information concerned, and the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the personal data have been or will be disclosed. However, this is not an absolute right and the interests of other individuals may restrict Your right of access. You may have the right to obtain a copy of the personal information undergoing processing free of charge. For further copies requested by You, we may charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs.
  * **Right to request rectification:** As provided by applicable data protection law, **** You have the right to obtain from us the rectification of inaccurate personal information concerning You. Depending on the purposes of the processing, You may have the right to have incomplete personal information completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
  * **Right to request erasure (right to be forgotten):** As provided by applicable data protection law, **Y** ou have the right to obtain from us the erasure of personal information concerning You and we may be obliged to erase such personal information.
  * **Right to request restriction of processing:** As provided by applicable data protection law, You have the right to obtain from us that we restrict the processing of Your personal information. In such case, the respective information will be marked and may only be processed by us for certain purposes.
  * **Right to request data portability:** As provided by applicable data protection law, **** You have the right to receive the personal information concerning You, which You have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and You may have the right to transmit those information to another entity without hindrance from us.
  * **Right to object:**

**Under certain circumstances, You have the right to object, on grounds relating to Your particular situation, at any time to the processing of Your personal information by us and we are required to no longer process Your personal information. Such right to object especially applies if we collect and process Your personal information for profiling purposes in order to better understand Your interests in our products and services or for certain types of direct marketing.**

**If You have a right to object and if You exercise this right, Your personal information will no longer be processed for such purposes by us.**

**Such a right to object may, in particular, not exist if the processing of Your personal information is necessary to take steps prior to entering into a contract or to perform a contract already concluded.**

  * **Right to withdraw Your consent:** If You have declared Your consent regarding certain collecting, processing and use of Your personal information (in particular regarding the receipt of direct marketing communication via email, SMS/MMS, fax, and telephone), You can withdraw this consent at any time with future effect. Such a withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of the processing prior to the consent withdrawal. 

To exercise Your rights, please contact us as stated under Section 13 below.You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent data protection supervisory authority in the relevant Member State (e.g., the place where You reside, work, or of an alleged infringement of the GDPR).

Back to Top 

**11\. Australian Supplier Portal**

**11.1** Raytheon may collect personal information if a business partner as a supplier registers or makes submissions on Raytheon’s Australian Supplier Portal (“Supplier Portal”).  The personal information collected from suppliers may include the address, date of birth, photograph, qualifications, work history, job title, educational history and security clearances of the supplier’s directors, officers, employees, agents and subcontractors. 

**11.2** Raytheon uses this information to register the supplier on the Supplier Portal and to assess submissions made by it.  

**11.3** This information may be disclosed to third parties that provide services to Raytheon relating to the assessment of supplier submissions and the management of the Supplier Portal including potentially to third parties located in USA and Norway.

**11.4** If Raytheon is unable to collect this information, the supplier may not be able to register on the Supplier Portal and Raytheon may not be able to assess submissions made by the supplier.

**11.5** You may request access to any personal information we hold about You, subject to certain exceptions (for example, if it would interfere with the privacy of others).  If You wish to access Your personal information, please contact us using the contact details in Section 13 below.

Back to Top 

**12\. Changes to This Privacy Notice**

Changes to this Privacy Notice, will be posted on this page, with a new effective date at the top. If we make material changes to our Privacy Notice that could affect the personal information You previously submitted to us, we will provide You notice and an appropriate opportunity to consent as required by law.

Back to Top 

**13\. Contact Information**

If You have any questions or concerns regarding Raytheon's Privacy Notice or its use of personal information or if You want to exercise Your rights as described in this Privacy Notice or as otherwise granted under applicable law, please contact us at [PrivacyPolicy@raytheon.com](mailto:PrivacyPolicy@Raytheon.com) or:

Chief Ethics and Compliance Officer  
RAYTHEON COMPANY  
Waltham Woods  
870 Winter Street Waltham, MA 02451-1449

Back to Top 

Back to Top __
